                                                                     
                                                                     
                                                                     
Lesson 18
Prepositional Phrases
A prepositional phrase is a group of words that begins with a preposition and usually
ends with a noun or a pronoun, called the object of the preposition. Adjectives and other
modifiers may be placed between the preposition and its object. A preposition may have
more than one object. 
He put the note into his pocket. (Pocket is the object of the preposition into.)
Prepositional phrases may occur sequentially in a sentence.
He put the note into the pocket of his shirt.
A prepositional phrase is usually used as an adjective or an adverb. When it is used as an
adjective, it modifies a noun or a pronoun. When it is used as an adverb, it modifies an
adjective, a verb, or another adverb.
We read the book about the West. (adjective phrase modifying the noun book)
Who around town could help us hang posters? (adjective phrase modifying the
pronoun who)
She parks her new car in the garage. (adverb phrase modifying the verb parks)
The job is easy for you. (adverb phrase modifying the adjective easy)
She reads well for her age. (adverb phrase modifying the adverb well)
 Exercise 1 Underline each prepositional phrase.
Icarus flew high before his fall.
1. Our cat made her bed under the table in the kitchen.
2. One never knows what wonderful worlds might be found between the covers of a book.
3. Our flight took us over the Rocky Mountains and the Grand Canyon.
4. Please have this list of items in stock in time for the holiday season.
5. Before summer vacation be sure to complete the entire reading list for extra credit.
6. Reserve the small conference room for the morning of March 22 from nine until noon.
7. The room across the hall is the public relations office.
8. We will wait until this evening to do the grocery shopping.
9. The book I needed was beneath a stack of papers under my bed.
10. The telephones inside her office can be heard outside the building.
Unit 3, Phrases 85
Copyright © by Glencoe/McGraw-Hill
Name ___________________________________________________ Class _________ Date ____________________
Grammar
Lesson 30
Sentence Fragments
A sentence fragment is an incomplete sentence. It may lack a subject, a verb, or both.
Alternatively, it may be a subordinate clause that cannot stand alone. Correct it by adding
the missing phrase or words.
Although the road stops. (fragment)
Although the road stops here, we can travel farther on foot. (sentence)
 Exercise 1 Write frag. next to each sentence fragment. Write S next to each complete sentence.
frag. In the event of a disaster.
1. Samuel Clemens became one of the best-loved American storytellers.
2. Because Misha had an innovative style.
3. Works from charcoals to watercolors to pastels.
4. Nancy, feeling that her ideas were unpopular, kept them to herself.
5. By distancing herself from historians, biographers, and critics.
6. In his paintings, David has developed a very individual style.
7. A concept that became apparent in 1915.
8. Id like to study at the Art Institute of Chicago or the Arts Students League in 
New York.
9. Willie Stieglitz, a promoter and art exhibitor.
10. Come in.
11. Whom he later called to apologize.
12. Myriads of flowers, some from her well-manicured gardens.
13. Appeared in the mid-1920s.
14. Many clothing designs have been influenced by the American Southwest landscape.
15. Where they first visited in 1995.
16. Establishing herself as the authority on short story writing.
17. Just give it a tweak and itll come on.
18. Long-stemmed purple irises rising from their beds.
19. Her perfume lingered in the air, revealing her recent presence.
Unit 4, Clauses and Sentence Structure 111
Copyright © by Glencoe/McGraw-Hill
Name ___________________________________________________ Class _________ Date ____________________
Grammar

