                                                                     
                                                                     
                                                                     
                                             
MY IBM EXPERIENCE :
1st round - series 18 que + apti 18 ques no -ve marks time 2.min 
apti - percentage, time distance , ratio n proportion basic ques but lengthy calculations.. so practise well

2nd round - english assessment test 22 ques ,20 min, no -ve marking, mcq
some ques which i remember
1. salutation of business letter n format like Dear Mr. Smith : 
2. blue pen in signatures used to prevent photocopy (T/F) true
3. Enclosures (3) meaning - documents attached
4. active voice
5. Passive voice
6. Ranny was with sally n me. true
Ranny was with sally n I.
Ranny was with me n Sally. find correct one
7.ques on correct usage of comma
8.what to include in business letter
- purpose
- reason of writing
- For whom intended
- all of above
ans . all of the above
9.Miss Sheela is dancer. Funny , arrogant and stylish. find type of error
- run out error
- sentence fragment (correct)
10. sentence with correct use of capitalize words
11. Meaning of Sexist lang
- words to distinguish betn male and female
12. whether assistant can sign on behalf of administrative  1officer . (T/F) false
13. how to end business letter
- regards
- sincerely
- respectfully
- 2 and 3 
ans is 2-and 3 .
3rd round - Tech + HR interview 15-20 min
basic hr ques , ur project, some basic prog may b asked like reverse
usually check confidence n communication..
14- The coachy my best friend play with me everyday. Write the sentence using comma, colon , semicolon at appropriate position

