                                                                     
                                                                     
                                                                     
                                             
http://www.m4maths.com/placement-puzzles.php?SOURCE=IBM = try this link for some more recent quant and series questions hopefully wil get 70% from this by doing first 20-25 page only make ur acount on this u can find answers also .
why ibm is called big blue ?
ans The company was founded in 1911 as the Computing Tabulating Recording Company (CTR) through a merger of three companies: the Tabulating Machine Company, the International Time Recording Company, and the Computing Scale Company.[4][5] CTR adopted the name International Business Machines in 1924, using a name previously designated to CTR's subsidiary in Canada and later South America. Securities analysts nicknamed IBM Big Blue in recognition of IBM's common use of blue in products, packaging, and logo.[6]
Big Blue is a nickname for IBM; several theories exist regarding its origin. One theory, substantiated by people who worked for IBM at the time, is that IBM field reps coined the term in the 1960s, referring to the color of the mainframes IBM installed in the 1960s and early 1970s. "All blue" was a term used to describe a loyal IBM customer, and business writers later picked up the term.[12][13] Another theory suggests that Big Blue simply refers to the Company's logo. A third theory suggests that Big Blue refers to a former company dress code that required many IBM employees to wear blue suits.[14][12]

Read more: Why is IBM called Big Blue? | Answerbag http://www.answerbag.com/q_view/145710#ixzz2pHiRxyt7
questions - what 8 bars in ibm logo says ?
answers-Logos designed in the 1970s tended to be sensitive to the technical limitations of photocopiers, which were then being widely deployed. A logo with large solid areas tended to be poorly copied by copiers in the 1970s, so companies preferred logos that avoided large solid areas. The 1972 IBM logos are an example of this tendency. With the advent of digital copiers in the mid-1980s this technical restriction had largely disappeared; at roughly the same time, the 13-bar logo was abandoned for almost the opposite reason  it was difficult to render accurately on the low-resolution digital printers (240 dots per inch) of the time.
The striped logo had both 13-bar and 8-bar versions. The 8-bar version is the one that's in use today.
permalink
[][deleted] 2 points 4 years ago
But it still could be both. That only gives the reason for having lines, they very easily could have chosen eight to represent a byte.
permalinkparent
[][deleted] 1 point 4 years ago
They chose 8 because it looked better on the 240DPI printers of the era.
permalinkparent

link-http://www.reddit.com/comments/9m1cs/til_that_the_ibm_logo_has_8_bars_in_each_of_the/?sort=controversial

questions -   why ibm is called blue elephant , ? find it yourself 

